♪ ♪
MADAME MORRIBLE (amplified):
Citizens of Oz,
there have been 12 tide turns
since the Wicked Witch
of the West escaped
with our Grimmerie.
Shield your children.
Trust no animals.
She will be eliminated.
(thunder crashes)
Until then,
the Wizard's vision
for the Oz of tomorrow
marches on.
(animal grumbles)
GUARD 1:
Do it! Move!
(bellows)
All right, load it up.
Come on! Let's go! Move!
GUARD 2:
No speaking.
The Wizard needs
the road finished.
(chatter continues)
- (steam hissing)
- (mechanical creaking)
♪ ♪
- (animals grumbling)
- GUARD 3: Move! Move!
GUARD 1:
Come on, let's go! Move!
GUARD 4:
Fill up that basket!
- Keep moving.
- (animal whimpers)
Come on.
(animals grumbling)
Come on. Keep moving.
(grunts) Get up!
(animal wailing)
- Come on. (grunts)
- (animal groaning)
(whoosh)
(grumbling)
Whoa. Settle down.
- (bellowing)
- (gasps)
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Get back! (gasps)
Retreat! Guards, retreat!
It's the Witch!
(screams, grunts)
(screams)
(grunting)
♪ ♪
(panting)
(monkeys screeching in distance)
♪ ♪
(sonic boom)
(panting)
The Witch! She's back!
♪ ♪
OZIANS:
♪ Every day, more Wicked ♪
♪ Every day, the terror grows ♪
♪ All of Oz is ever on alert ♪
♪ That's the way with Wicked ♪
♪ Spreading fear
where'er she goes ♪
♪ Seeking out new victims
she can hurt ♪
MADAME MORRIBLE: ♪ Like some
terrible green blizzard ♪
♪ Throughout the land,
she flies ♪
♪ Defaming our poor Wizard ♪
♪ With her calumnies and lies ♪
- OZIANS: ♪ She lies ♪
- (monkeys screeching)
♪ She lies ♪
(Ozians vocalizing)
Go, go!
GUARD:
Release them!
♪ ♪
♪ Save us from the Wicked ♪
♪ Shield us
so we won't be hexed ♪
♪ Give us warning:
Where will she strike next? ♪
♪ Where will she strike next? ♪
♪ Where will she strike ♪
♪ Next? ♪
♪ When I stop the Wizard ♪
♪ All Oz will applaud ♪
♪ How I saved them
from the Wizard ♪
♪ By revealing he's a fraud ♪
♪ If I can just make them
believe in the truth ♪
♪ That all that he says
is a lie ♪
♪ That's when
they'll finally bid ♪
♪ The Wizard goodbye ♪
ELPHABA:
Come with me.
GLINDA:
What?
ELPHABA:
To meet the Wizard.
PALACE GUARD:
The Wizard will see you now.
(train chugging,
whistle blows)
♪ Dearest Glinda,
you are still the best ♪
Well, I guess.
♪ Others are Good,
but you're the Goodliest ♪
♪ We feel merry,
we feel cheery ♪
♪ Just to gaze
on your reflection ♪
♪ Only you disprove the theory ♪
- ♪ That you can't improve
perfection ♪ -(sighs)
Thank you.
Good. Good. Good. Good. Good.
Good.
(gasps)
(students gasp)
She's so Good.
- (murmurs of agreement)
- (Ozians cheering)
OZIAN ANNOUNCER (amplified):
Glinda the Good.
- ♪ La, la ♪
- (cheering continues)
♪ La, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
- ♪ La, la ♪
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
- ♪ La, la ♪ -♪ La, la, la,
la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
- ♪ La, la ♪
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
- ♪ La, la ♪ -♪ La, la, la,
la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ ♪
- (grunt in unison)
- Hup!
OZIANS:
♪ Save us from the Wicked ♪
♪ Every night, our voices wail ♪
- ♪ Save us from this fear ♪
- (train whistle blows)
♪ And victimhood ♪
(train whistle blows)
- ♪ We believe in Glinda ♪
- (confetti popping)
♪ With her magic,
she'll prevail ♪
♪ She will make it end ♪
♪ The way it should ♪
(Ozians cheering)
♪ When at last
the Wicked is defeated ♪
♪ By the Good ♪
♪ The Good ♪
♪ Wicked is defeated ♪
- ♪ By the Good. ♪
- (popping)
(Ozians cheering)
PFANNEE:
There's a quoncert in Quox,
if you want to attend,
next week.
GLINDA:
Oh. Perhaps.
Uh, The Quadling Quorum
wants to honor you.
They're just not sure
for what yet.
Good to hear.
And someone sent pastries.
(chuckles) Good for us.
Hey, send these
to my hovel, please.
The gowns from last week?
PFANNEE: Oh, maybe, uh, give
to the under-fortunate.
- SHENSHEN: Oh, of course.
- GLINDA: (gasps) Good idea.
- (grunting)
- And, you know,
while we're at it,
we really should
look into trademarking
the word "good."
- Ooh. That's go--
- Ooh.
- I mean, I'm goosified.
- (chuckles)
My follicles are screaming.
- I love my job so much.
- GLINDA: Aw. Good.
(gasps) Madame Morrible.
Forgive me
for keeping you waiting.
I had no idea.
Has something happened?
Is it Elphaba?
You mean the Wicked Witch?
Right, of course.
- Come in, come in.
- SHENSHEN: Mrs. Morrible...
Would you like us
to take minutes for you?
...I c-- I can, I can get you,
like, a little snack.
You want a little snack?
Like a cherry frazzle
or a juice puff?
"Mrs. Morrible"?
She's not married.
You sh... (groans)
MADAME MORRIBLE:
With the Yellow Brick Road
grand opening ahead
and the Wicked Witch attacks
growing bolder,
the public is on edge.
So it's more important than ever
that you lift
everyone's spirits,
as only you can.
(chuckles) Accordingly.
(gasps)
Oh, Madame, I love it.
What is it?
Your new mode of transport.
Your very own
vehicular spherical globule.
So, like, a bubble?
Sure.
(Madame Morrible sighs)
(Glinda gasps)
Was that supposed to happen?
It's all right.
GLINDA:
Are you sure?
Wha--
Does that do
what I think it does?
(gasps)
(muffled):
No!
(gasps)
(muffled):
I can't.
(clearly):
No way!
(Glinda giggles, screams)
(gasps)
(muffled):
I'm obsessulated.
The Wizard had it crafted
especially for you.
His Ozness feels it vital
that you, as our Good Witch,
also be airborne.
(muffled):
I agree.
But don't fret over
your inability
to produce any actual magic.
This invention will
disguise your deficiency.
The bubble's mechanism
is cleverly concealed.
People will assume that
you are causing it to float
through your own witchly powers.
- (chuckles)
- So, just let them assume.
Right.
But don't forget this.
(gasps)
(exhales sharply)
The wand really sells it.
I'll see you
at the opening ceremony.
(muffled):
Thank you so much.
♪ ♪
(children laughing)
YOUNG GALINDA:
A magic wand?
CHILDREN:
Happy birthday, Galinda.
(laughter)
It's what I've wanted
most of all.
Come on, give it a go.
- Yeah, try it out!
- (excited chatter)
(chanting): Magic! Magic!
Magic! Magic! Magic!
CHILD:
Come on.
(laughter)
(children murmuring
and whispering)
Oh. (giggles)
I forgot to say the spell.
- Oh! -Oh, yeah.
- (overlapping chatter)
- The wand. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
- (giggling)
I hereby commandify that
something magical shall happen!
- CHILD: She can't even make
a spark. -(children murmuring)
Look! There's a rainbow.
- (children murmuring)
- CHILD: Wow.
Did you make that?
Um...
Well, you know
how I love rainbows.
- (Popsicle laughs)
- (children cheering) -Oh, wow!
(excited chatter)
CHILD:
That's my friend!
(excited chatter continues)
POPSICLE (singsongy):
Go see the rainbow!
MOMSIE:
Isn't it fantastic?
POPSICLE:
Who is ready for some cake?
- Go see Rosie and Posie.
- (excited chatter)
MOMSIE:
What's wrong, dearest?
You got everything you wanted.
I know,
but I want to be magical.
For real.
And... I'm not.
Oh, but, darlingest,
everyone loves you.
Believe me,
that's all you'll ever need.
Where's that smile?
That's my girl.
(lively chatter and laughter
continues)
♪ ♪
Sweetheart, you coming?
Come on!
(Ozians cheering)
(cheering continues)
♪ ♪
(Ozians exclaiming)
(cheering continues)
Glinda!
Fellow Ozians, good news.
Now, at last,
all roads lead to the Wizard.
♪ Oh, what a celebration
we'll have today ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Let's have a celebration
the Glinda way ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Finally, a day that's totally
Wicked Witch-free ♪
♪ We couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
(cheering)
MADAME MORRIBLE:
Thank Goodness for you, Glinda,
and your handsome swain,
Prince Fiyero,
newly appointed captain
of the Gale Force--
assembled by the Wizard himself
to capture the Wicked Witch.
Tell us, Captain.
How does it feel?
It's frustrating.
But I became captain
to find her,
and I will keep on searching
until I do.
- No!
- (feedback squeals)
Being engaged.
(Ozians gasping)
- (laughing)
- (cheering)
We're engaged?
Surprised?
Yes. (chuckles)
Good. We hoped you'd be.
Um, the Wizard and I.
(Ozians aahing)
♪ We couldn't be happier ♪
Right, dear?
♪ Couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Right here ♪
♪ Look what we've got,
a fairy-tale plot ♪
♪ Our very own happy ending ♪
- (Ozians aahing)
- ♪ Where we ♪
♪ Couldn't be happier ♪
True, dear?
♪ And we're happy to share ♪
♪ Our ending vicariously ♪
♪ With all of you ♪
♪ He couldn't look handsomer ♪
♪ I couldn't feel humbler ♪
♪ We couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Because happy is
what happens ♪
♪ When all your dreams
come true ♪
(Ozians gasping, cheering)
MADAME MORRIBLE: And, Glinda,
dear, we are happy for you.
As Press Secretary,
I've striven to ensure
that all of Oz knows
the story of your braverism
in the face of the terrifying
Wicked Witch of the West.
(Ozians gasping)
♪ I hear she has an extra eye ♪
- ♪ That always remains awake ♪
- (Ozians murmuring)
♪ I hear that she can
shed her skin ♪
- ♪ As easily as a snake ♪
- (Ozians gasping)
♪ I hear some rebel animals ♪
♪ Are giving her
food and shelter ♪
♪ I hear her soul
is so unclean ♪
♪ Pure water can melt her ♪
- Mmm. Darling?
- OZIANS: ♪ Melt her ♪
♪ Please, somebody,
go and melt her ♪
People are so empty-headed,
- they'll believe anything.
- (chuckles softly)
If you'll excuse us
just a clock-tick. (chuckles)
Come with me, dearest.
(Ozians cheering)
What is going on?
People are watching.
I can't just
stand there grinning,
pretending to go along
with all this.
Do you think
I like hearing them say
those awful things about her?
I hate it.
Then what are we doing here?
Let's go. Let's go.
- Let's just get out of here.
- I-I can't.
I can't when there are
people looking to me
to raise their spirits.
You can't leave
because you can't resist this.
That's the truth.
Well, maybe I can't.
Is that so wrong?
I mean, who could?
Well, you know who could.
We both know
who could and who has.
And I have to find her,
because if someone else
gets there first, she...
Fiyero, I'm worried
for her, too.
And I miss her.
Can't you see
she doesn't want to be found?
You've got to face it.
She's made her choice.
You're right.
And, look...
...if it makes you happy,
of course I'll marry you.
It'll make you happy,
too, right?
You know me. I'm always happy.
Fiyero.
(Ozians cheering)
Thanks plenty, dearest.
He's, um... he's gone
to fetch me a refreshment.
(Ozians aahing)
He's so thoughtful that way.
♪ That's why ♪
♪ I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ No, I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Though it is, I admit ♪
♪ The tiniest bit ♪
♪ Unlike I anticipated ♪
♪ But I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Simply couldn't be happier ♪
Well, not "simply."
♪ 'Cause getting your dreams ♪
♪ It's strange, but it seems ♪
♪ A little, well, complicated ♪
♪ There's a kind of a sort of ♪
♪ Cost ♪
♪ There's a couple
of things get ♪
♪ Lost ♪
♪ There are bridges you cross
you didn't know you crossed ♪
♪ Until you've crossed ♪
♪ And if that joy ♪
♪ That thrill ♪
♪ Doesn't thrill
like you think it will ♪
♪ Still ♪
♪ With this perfect finale ♪
♪ The cheers and the ballyhoo ♪
♪ Who wouldn't be happier? ♪
♪ So I couldn't be happier ♪
♪ Because happy
is what happens ♪
♪ When all your dreams ♪
♪ Come true ♪
Well, isn't it?
♪ Happy is what happens ♪
♪ When your dreams ♪
♪ Come true ♪
OZIANS: ♪ We love you, Glinda,
if we may be so frank ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ For all this joy, we know
who we've got to thank ♪
♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ That means the Wizard,
Glinda ♪
♪ And fiancé ♪
♪ They couldn't be Goodlier ♪
♪ She couldn't be lovelier ♪
♪ We couldn't be luckier ♪
♪ I couldn't be happier ♪
- ♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ Thank Goodness for today ♪
- (fireworks popping, whistling)
- ♪ Thank Goodness ♪
♪ For today. ♪
(Ozians cheering)
- (whooshing)
- (Ozians gasping, murmuring)
It's the Wicked Witch!
Take cover!
- Mount up!
- (Ozians clamoring, screaming)
(fireworks popping)
MADAME MORRIBLE:
Glinda!
Take cover, everyone!
GLINDA: Everyone, please,
don't be alarmed.
(wind whistling)
She won't hurt you. It's okay.
She wants to kill us all!
Look!
♪ ♪
(clamoring and screaming
continue)
Gale Force, go!
(monkeys screeching)
- (horse neighing)
- FIYERO: Hyah!
Fiyero!
Hyah! Come on! Hyah!
No, come.
- (monkeys hooting)
- (soldiers shouting)
(monkeys screeching)
(grunting, panting)
(grunts)
Halt!
(horses sputtering softly)
(birds calling in distance)
♪ ♪
(breathing heavily)
SOLDIER:
Captain, do you see anything?
No.
Come on.
We must not rest until
we capture that Wicked Witch.
(sighs)
Come on! Let's go!
- Move out.
- Fall in.
♪ ♪
(whooshing)
(frustrated grunt)
Fiyero.
Even you.
♪ ♪
(faint laughter)
(birds chirping)
(wind whistling softly)
♪ ♪
(door opens)
AVARIC:
Madam Governor?
That proposed new regulation,
the Animal Anti-Motility law.
What law?
Animals would need
a permit to travel.
AVARIC:
Munchkinland is the one place
in Oz it hasn't been ratified.
The League of Governors
is urging you to sign.
Nessa, you're not
going to sign that.
But if I don't...
people will say,
"She's just like her sister."
Give us a clock-tick, Avaric.
Boq, forgive me.
It's just that Elphaba
abandoned me when I needed her.
She didn't even come see me
when Father died.
Only you did that.
Oz only knows how I'd have coped
with all of this without you.
And I'm glad
I could be there for you.
But I've been thinking
for a while now...
Yes?
I think it's time I moved on.
I see.
Well, if that's how you feel,
I think it's best you leave.
Now.
Nessa, this won't be the
last time we'll see each other.
Oh, I know.
(door opens, closes)
- ANNOUNCER: Attention,
passengers. -(whistle blowing)
This is the final boarding
for the Emerald City Unlimited.
Doors will be closing shortly.
Please step inside and make way
for boarding passengers.
(busy chatter)
♪ ♪
ANNOUNCER:
Visiting someone special?
Get a new Ozfit.
Visit the Wizard's Emporium
in downtown Emerald City.
- (knocks)
- TICKET ASSISTANT: Next.
Oh.
Excuse me.
Um, my train is boarding in...
Travel permit?
- What?
- All Munchkins are forbidden
to leave Munchkinland
without express written
permission of the Governor.
She insisted it go
into effect immediately.
ANNOUNCER:
...reminder to all passengers...
MUNCHKIN PARENT 1:
Stop pushing me.
- MUNCHKIN PARENT 2: Elsa.
- TRAIN STATION OFFICIAL: Go!
- What's happening?
- Keep your hands off my family.
I don't want to hear it,
Munchkins.
Move! Forward now, Munchkins.
GUARD:
Go.
MUNCHKIN PARENT 1:
This is outrageous.
- You cannot treat us like this.
- Go!
Move along, Munchkins.
TICKET ASSISTANT:
Next.
MUNCHKIN PARENT 2:
This is not the Oz I know.
- This is un-Ozian.
- Back in line.
- Step back. What did I say?
- (Munchkins clamoring)
Step-- Munchkins, step back.
Back in line.
(fabric rustling)
(wind whistling)
♪ ♪
(animals bellowing and calling)
GUIDE ANIMAL:
Watch your footing.
Next group. Come on, children.
Let's move.
We have to leave now.
GUIDE ANIMAL 2:
Stay together!
- Come along now.
- (animals grunting, calling)
Keep moving.
Eyes on your children, please.
Don't worry, I'm with you.
I'll never leave you.
Don't go too fast.
- What is all this?
- GUIDE ANIMAL: Watch your step.
ELPHABA:
What are you doing?
Come, children. Quickly.
We must get out of Oz.
Don't do this. Please.
- Keep moving.
- Don't leave Oz.
Join with me.
Help me fight the Wizard.
(scoffs) And wait for
the monkeys to carry us off?
That's what happens
to animals who speak out.
And they're never seen again.
No.
Oz wouldn't be Oz
without all of you.
And I know you're frightened,
but this is home.
Belongs to all of us.
- DULCIBEAR: Elphaba.
- (animals gasping, murmuring)
(birds squawking)
Dulcibear.
Oh, little one.
I've missed your bear hugs.
(Dulcibear sighs)
We can't stay here.
It's become rotten.
There's only one thing left
for us to do:
escape through that tunnel
to The Place Beyond Oz.
They say The Place Beyond Oz
is just...
...emptiness.
(wind whistling)
How will you survive?
How will you survive here?
No one in Oz will be happy
until you're dead.
(animals murmuring)
♪ ♪
Why would you want to stay?
I don't know.
♪ Why do I love this place ♪
♪ That's never loved me? ♪
♪ A place that seems
to be devolving ♪
♪ And even wanting to ♪
♪ But Oz is more than
just a place ♪
♪ It's a promise, an idea ♪
♪ And I want to help
make it come true ♪
♪ Why should a land have
so much meaning ♪
♪ When dark times befall it? ♪
♪ It's only land ♪
♪ Made of dirt and rock
and loam ♪
♪ It's just a place
that's familiar ♪
♪ And home's just
what we call it ♪
♪ But there's no place
like home ♪
♪ Don't we all know ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
Try to understand.
We just can't fight anymore.
We have to.
(animals murmuring)
♪ When you feel
you can't fight anymore ♪
♪ Just tell yourself ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
♪ When you feel
it's not worth fighting for ♪
♪ Compel yourself ♪
♪ Because there's no place
like home ♪
♪ When you want to leave ♪
♪ Discouraged and resigned ♪
♪ That's what
they want you to do ♪
♪ But think how you will grieve
for all you leave behind ♪
♪ Oz belongs to you, too ♪
(animals murmuring)
♪ Those who would take it
from you ♪
♪ Spout a lie to sell yourself ♪
♪ You go their way or go ♪
♪ It's them we'll be defeating ♪
♪ If we keep on repeating ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
♪ There's no place ♪
♪ Like home ♪
♪ There's no place like home ♪
(hooting)
♪ If we just keep fighting
for it ♪
♪ We will win back
and restore it ♪
♪ There's no place ♪
♪ Like... ♪
- Don't listen to her! (gasps)
- (animals gasping)
(animals murmuring)
(whimpers)
At night, when I close my eyes,
I still see that green face.
(whimpers)
I can't believe it. Is that you?
Stay back!
When I was just a cub,
she snatched me from
the only home I ever knew.
ELPHABA:
You were in a cage.
If I'd have left you there,
you would never
have learned to speak.
They say she's the one
who gave the monkeys wings
and gave the Wizard his spies.
- ANIMAL: Is this true?
- (animals murmuring)
- It's true.
- (animals gasping)
I cast that spell.
And I have to live with that.
(screeches)
If I'd have known
I was being tricked,
if I'd have known why,
I would never have...
- The Wizard lies.
- (animals chittering)
I can prove it.
And if we stand together...
Dulcibear!
Little one,
I know you'll keep fighting,
because I know you.
♪ ♪
Thank you, Boq.
Perhaps a friendly game
of cards once I'm done working?
Whatever you say,
Madam Governor.
I asked you to call me Nessa.
Remember?
Boq.
Never mind. I'll call you
when I've finished.
♪ ♪
(wind whistling softly)
Now, who could have left
that door open?
- (Nessarose gasps)
- I did.
It's so good to see you.
Why are you here?
I've tried to keep you
out of all of this, but...
I need you.
Thought you might have come
to apologize.
Apologize?
Our father died of shame,
and you didn't even bother
to show up.
You might at least
pretend to be sorry.
For what? He hated me.
That's a Wicked thing to say.
No, it's not.
It's just the truth.
Do you know why?
What does it matter now?
You're right.
Doesn't matter.
Because it's just us.
You're the Governor.
People will listen to you,
- and together, we...
- Why should I help you?
You fly around Oz
with that book,
helping animals
you've never even met,
and not once
have you ever thought
- to use your powers to help me.
- You never wanted my help.
I do now!
I want to go back to the way
we were at school.
That night when Boq told me
I was beautiful.
(faint ballroom chatter)
It was the first time
I ever wore these shoes.
There was music.
(inhales deeply)
And everything was
still possible.
♪ That night at the Ozdust ♪
♪ Boq danced with me there ♪
♪ And it felt like
he loved me then ♪
♪ That night when I felt
I was floating on air ♪
♪ I want to feel that again ♪
Make me feel that again!
Nessa, I wish there was
something I could do, but...
(wind whistling softly)
"Ambulahn dare,
pahto, pahpoot.
"Ambulahn dasca,
- lahfenahto."
- What are you doing?
- "Ambulahn dare, pahto,
pahpoot. -(faint rumbling)
- Ambulahn dasca, caldapess."
- Oh.
- Oh, my shoes.
- "Lahfenahto, lahfenahtum."
NESSAROSE: Oh, they feel like
they're on fire!
- "Pede, pede, caldapess!
- (rumbling, creaking)
- Pede, pede, caldapess!"
- (screams, chuckles)
♪ ♪
(gasping)
(laughing)
I'm floating on air.
Oh, Nessa. At last.
♪ I'd always been
unsure I could ♪
♪ But finally,
from these powers ♪
- ♪ Something good ♪
- (laughing)
Finally.
♪ Something good ♪
Thank you, Elphaba.
BOQ:
Nessa?
He called me Nessa.
It's working.
Nessa, there's something
I have to...
Look.
You.
- Boq.
- Stay back!
It's just me.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
NESSAROSE:
Boq, don't be afraid.
Elphaba just came
to lift my spirits.
You did this to make her happy?
NESSAROSE:
I know now anything is possible
for both of us.
- ♪ Nessa? ♪
- Yes?
♪ Uh, Nessa, surely now ♪
♪ I'll matter less to you ♪
♪ And you won't mind
my leaving here tonight ♪
Leaving?
♪ The moment when I read ♪
♪ Glinda's going to be wed ♪
♪ To Fiyero ♪
Glinda?
♪ Yes, Nessa, that's right ♪
♪ And I've got to go
appeal to her ♪
♪ Express the way
I feel to her ♪
Nessa.
I lost my heart to Glinda
the moment I first saw her.
Lost your heart?
We'll see about that.
- Let him go.
- Don't come any closer!
You and your sister.
She's as Wicked as you are,
keeping me here like a prisoner.
What are you talking about?
I am talking about my life!
The little that's left of it.
NESSAROSE: You're going to lose
your heart to me, I tell you!
If I have to...
I have to...
...magic spell you.
There must be a magic spell
in here to capture your heart.
- Nessa, no. That's dangerous.
- What is she doing?
"Ah tum, ta tayk..."
- Stop, Nessa!
- "...ah tum, cortum."
You're pronouncing the words
all wrong!
- Wh-What is she saying?
- "Ah tum, ta tayk."
- I'm going.
- (soft whooshing)
- NESSAROSE: "Ah tum."
- (sharp whoosh)
(gasps)
- (creaking)
- (groaning)
- Boq, what is it?
- (panting)
(groans) My heart.
(heart beating and creaking)
It feels like it's sh--
like it's shrinking.
- Do something!
- ELPHABA: I can't!
A spell from the Grimmerie
can never be reversed.
NESSAROSE:
Boq? This is all your fault!
- If you hadn't come here...
- I have to find another spell.
It's the only thing
that might work.
Go, now! Go!
(pained groaning)
(heartbeat continues faster)
♪ Save him, please,
just save him ♪
- ♪ My poor Boq, my sweet ♪
- "Ambulahn dasca."
♪ My brave him ♪
- ♪ Don't leave me till ♪
- "Lahfenahto."
♪ My sorry life has ceased ♪
- "Caldapess."
- (groans)
♪ Alone and loveless here ♪
♪ With just the girl
in the mirror ♪
♪ Just her and me ♪
♪ The Wicked Witch of the East ♪
- (Boq groans)
- (metal clicking)
♪ We deserve each other. ♪
(door closes)
He's sleeping now.
What about his heart?
It's all right.
He won't need one now.
The wedding.
Wait, where are you going?
All the most influential people
in Oz will be there.
It's the perfect opportunity
to show them all the truth
about the Wizard.
Oh, please.
Stop lying to yourself.
You're going there to find
Fiyero, but it's too late.
Nessa, I have done
everything I could for you,
and it hasn't been enough.
Nothing ever will be.
Elphaba, don't leave me!
Goodbye, Nessa.
I'm off to see the Wizard.
♪ ♪
- (clattering in other room)
- (Boq groaning)
BOQ:
Where am I?
What happened?
(chuckles)
It's all right, dearest.
You just...
- (banging on door)
- (Boq grunting)
♪ ♪
(footsteps clanking)
What have you done?
It wasn't me.
I tried to stop her.
(metal squeaking)
Boq, please.
(breathing heavily)
What have you done to me?
You witch!
It wasn't me! It was her!
It was Elphaba!
♪ ♪
(grunts)
(breathing shakily)
Boq!
MADAME MORRIBLE (amplified):
Ozians of the Emerald City,
today the winds shift
and destiny unfolds
before our very eyes...
- THE WIZARD: Mm-hmm.
- ...for on this night,
by the glorification
of our Wizard,
Glinda the Good
and Prince Fiyero Tigelaar
join hands in unification.
Do I have everything I need?
No, I need an earring, please.
- Thank you.
- (chittering)
Something oldish? Yes.
MADAME MORRIBLE: This is
more than just a wedding.
It is a coronation
of hope itself.
(gears cranking)
GLINDA:
Something new?
(chuckles) Absolutely.
MADAME MORRIBLE:
So let the very foundations
of Oz shimmer
with celebratorium...
- (excited chatter)
- Let's go!
...for today,
Oz writes a new chapter.
Rejoicify,
and Oz shall shine forevermore.
(Ozians cheering)
(Glinda chuckles)
GLINDA:
Something bartered.
And something askew.
I need something askew.
- (bang on door)
- (gasps)
(glass tinkling and crackling)
Just give me a clock-tick.
Elphaba Thropp,
I know you're out here.
Just come in
before the monkeys spot you.
(Glinda gasps)
Elphaba.
Galinda.
Get in. Go.
♪ ♪
Elphie.
Thank Oz you're alive.
Careful. Your dress.
I still can't believe you
get around on that old thing.
Well, we can't all
come and go by bubble.
True.
(chuckles softly)
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I just wanted
to come and see you.
That means a lot to me, Elphie.
But if anyone
discoverates you...
I know. I know.
You never saw me.
I was never here.
Do you understand?
No. I can't bear this anymore.
I'm taking you
to see the Wizard.
Absolutely not.
- Yes.
- No!
This is between
the Wizard and I.
(sighs) I understand.
But you have to trust me.
I know how to talk to him,
- and maybe I could help work
something out. -(whooshing)
(gasps)
♪ ♪
(The Wizard scatting)
(chuckling)
(scatting)
- (model train whistle blows)
- ♪ Since I've... ♪
- (bell dings)
- (scatting)
What?
(soft whoosh)
(The Wizard scatting)
- (whistle blows)
- (model train chugging)
- (scatting)
- (gears rattling and clanking)
♪ ♪
(whistle blows)
(jingling)
ELPHABA:
You're done.
It's over.
I had a hunch
you'd be coming back to me.
I'm not here for you.
I'm here for Oz.
GLINDA:
Elphaba.
You know, you could've
just exited normally.
Just use the door.
Hello?
- ELPHABA: (sighs) Yes?
- Don't hate me.
It's my wedding day,
and you cannot refuse
a wedding wish.
Well, you can, but it's rude.
ELPHABA: I don't have time
for this. Now, listen.
You and I are gonna go
down there together,
and you are gonna admit
to her guests
that you have no real power
and that you cannot read
the Grimmerie.
(laughing)
Why is that funny?
Elphaba, uh, I've missed you.
(sighs) Can't we start again?
Yes. Please.
- Just say yes.
- No.
Don't you think I wish I could?
I would give anything
to go back to a time when I...
...when I actually believed
that you were Wonderful.
"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz."
No one believed in you
more than I did.
But there's no going back.
And we can't move forward,
not until everyone knows
what I know.
And once they know the truth...
They're not gonna believe it.
How can you say that?
Well, I'm just being straight
with you.
I could tell 'em
that I'd been lying to 'em
till I'm-- forgive me--
blue in the face,
but wouldn't make
any difference.
They're never gonna stop
believing in me.
You know why?
Because they don't want to.
♪ ♪
♪ Take it from
a wise, old carny ♪
♪ Once folks buy into
your blarney ♪
♪ It becomes the thing
they'll most hold on to ♪
♪ Once they've swallowed
sham and hokum ♪
♪ Facts and logic
won't unchoke 'em ♪
♪ They'll go on believing
what they want to ♪
♪ Show them exactly
what's the score ♪
(Glinda chuckles)
♪ They'll just believe it
even more ♪
(softly):
Watch this.
(grunts)
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ They called me Wonderful ♪
♪ So I said ♪
♪ "Wonderful? If you insist" ♪
(Glinda gasps, chuckles)
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ I will be Wonderful ♪
♪ Believe me,
it's hard to resist ♪
♪ 'Cause it feels Wonderful ♪
♪ They think he's Wonderful ♪
♪ Hey, look who's Wonderful ♪
♪ This corn-fed hick ♪
♪ Who said, "It might be keen ♪
♪ "To build a town of green ♪
♪ And a wonderful road
of yellow brick" ♪
Ow!
(The Wizard chuckling)
Bee-keek, beak-beak.
(chuckles)
Elphie, let's be honest.
Your way hasn't worked.
But if you join forces with us,
if people see that you're with
us, they'll begin to trust you.
You'll accomplish so much more.
Yeah, yeah. So much more.
You know, we could be
like a... like a family.
You know, I've never
really had a family.
Lucky you.
That's why I've wanted
to give the citizens of Oz...
everything.
- So you lied to them?
- No.
No.
No-- Well, um...
only v-verbally.
But those were the lies
that they wanted to hear.
♪ The truth is not
a thing of fact or reason ♪
♪ The truth is just
what everyone agrees on ♪
You see, back where I come from,
we got a whole lot of people
who believe
all sorts of things
that aren't true.
You know what we call it?
History.
Ooh.
- ♪ A man's called a traitor ♪
- (bell dings)
♪ Or liberator ♪
♪ A rich man's a thief ♪
♪ Or philanthropist ♪
♪ Is one an invader ♪
♪ Or noble crusader? ♪
♪ It's all in which label
is able to persist ♪
♪ There are precious few
at ease ♪
♪ With moral ambiguities ♪
♪ So we act as though
they don't exist ♪
It's not my best pupil.
♪ They call him Wonderful ♪
♪ So I am Wonderful ♪
♪ He is so Wonderful ♪
♪ It's part of his name ♪
♪ And with our help,
you can be the same ♪
GLINDA:
Come with me.
Elphie, aren't you tired
of running?
Think of what we could do.
Together.
♪ Unlimited ♪
♪ Together we're unlimited ♪
♪ Together we'll be ♪
♪ The greatest team
there's ever been ♪
♪ Elphie ♪
♪ Dreams the way
we planned 'em ♪
(Glinda giggles)
♪ If we work in tandem ♪
♪ There's no fight
we cannot win ♪
♪ At long, long last,
receive your due ♪
♪ Long overdue ♪
♪ Elphaba, a celebration
throughout Oz ♪
♪ That's all to do ♪
♪ With you ♪
(Glinda and The Wizard
chuckling)
♪ ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ They'll call you Wonderful ♪
♪ Come and be Wonderful ♪
THE WIZARD:
♪ Trust me, it's fun ♪
- ♪ We will be Wonderful ♪
- (laughing)
- ♪ You'll make me Wonderful ♪
- (squeals)
♪ Wonderful, Wonderful ♪
♪ ♪
(Elphaba and Glinda chuckling)
(Glinda squeals)
(growling)
♪ ♪
(deep, grating voice):
Who are you?
And why do you seek me?
Wait.
(music stops)
♪ It's possible I could agree ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ But this time ♪
♪ You have to prove yourself
to me ♪
No more blaming the animals.
And the ones
who've left Oz should be
free to return without fear.
THE WIZARD:
Hey, with you by my side,
I'm not gonna need to blame
the animals anymore.
You're not gonna need
spies, either,
so set the monkeys free.
(softly):
Oh, yeah? Hang on. Hang on.
(The Wizard sighs heavily)
Why? Why?
I think I got it.
Um...
Done.
GLINDA:
(gasps) I did it.
I mean, we did it.
(gasps)
I'll see you two
in a clock-tick.
Elphie, I'm so happy.
- (giggles)
- (chuckles)
(giggles) I'm getting married.
(squeals)
So, you want me to prove myself?
Oh, my gosh.
Look in your hand.
How'd that get there?
It's a key. It's a key.
(laughing):
Aren't you surprised?
I liked that dance.
That was fun. Come here.
Now, (clears throat)
I've been keeping them
locked in here, um,
for their own safety.
(monkeys chattering)
But, ah, no need
for that anymore.
Okay.
Hey, you want to come
over here and do the honors?
Uh, 'cause if you put that
in-in here, it'll let 'em go.
And, uh, I...
Gosh, I-I hope you feel good
about this whole thing, 'cause,
well, you've won,
but I think we all have.
- (heavy creaking)
- (monkeys chattering)
(chattering intensifies)
Chistery.
(gruff breathing)
Nothing can change
what's been done to you.
Well... what I've done.
But at least
you have your freedom now.
- Chistery, can you speak?
- (grunts)
Please try.
Well... go on.
You're free.
Fly.
(screeching)
(monkeys screeching)
Fly.
Fly!
♪ ♪
Wonderful. Uh...
Well...
Hey, if you and I
are gonna go down there
and greet those fancy folks,
I'd better, uh, spruce up.
(chuckling)
Chistery, what's wrong?
(heavy rumble)
♪ ♪
(quiet murmuring)
(instruments playing
gentle music)
(Ozians whispering, gasping)
(gentle music continues)
(animals murmuring)
- (animals clamoring)
- (bars and chains rattling)
♪ ♪
(animals clamoring)
(clamoring continues)
(applause)
(both chuckle softly)
(clamoring continues)
Dr. Dillamond.
Can't you speak?
It's me, Elphaba.
(bleating)
THE WIZARD:
Let me explain, 'cause th--
this is not what it looks like.
- (animals clamoring)
- (bars and chains rattling)
Elphaba, some animals
cannot be trusted.
Yes.
I know that now.
(clamoring continues)
And these sacred vows
- are to be entered into
- (distant clamoring)
not lightly but merrily.
Elphaba, try to understand.
No.
I'm not a bad man. I'm just a...
Yes, you are.
You're a very bad man.
(clamoring and rattling
growing louder)
You once asked me
what my heart's desire was,
and I know now what that is.
And that is to fight you
till the day I die!
- (locks snapping)
- (The Wizard grunts)
(growling)
- (breathing heavily)
- (clamoring quiets)
Run.
- (animals clamoring wildly)
- (birds squawking)
(grunting)
Wha-- (grunting)
And do you, Glinda...
- (distant clamoring)
- (Ozians murmuring)
What is that horrendible sound?
- (screaming)
- (animals clamoring wildly)
- (gasps)
- (Ozians screaming)
(grunts)
- (gasps)
- Move!
(clamoring and screaming
continue)
Stay there.
- (grunting)
- (screaming)
Fiyero!
(whimpering)
(screaming)
(clamoring continues)
This is the work
of the Wicked Witch!
She wants to kill us all!
(grunting)
(screams)
(frog croaks)
(grunts)
(bird calling)
(muttering, grunting)
No-- (groaning)
(straining)
How does it feel to have
your voice taken away?
(grunts)
Silence, Witch!
(sighs)
Water.
Lots of it. Bring water!
GUARD:
Yes, sir.
As much as you can carry.
A little help? (coughs weakly)
- Ah. (inhales sharply)
- (broomstick creaking)
Please.
(grunts)
(sighs) Thank you.
That was, uh, unpleasant.
Well, I think my trachea
is otherwi--
What? What are you doing?
- Shush, you. Get in.
- What?
Get in.
Unless you want
the guests to know
the truth about their Wizard.
- (The Wizard groans)
- Get in!
THE WIZARD:
Yes, yes.
♪ ♪
Your Ozness!
Fiyero. What are you...
What is happening?
What's happened is that
these two traitors...
Not another word, Your Ozness.
Darling, have you misplaced
your mind?
What are you doing?
(sighs)
I'm going with her.
- What?
Let's go.
- Let's go.
Wait. What?
You mean to tell me
that the two of you...
- This whole time?
- No, it wasn't like that.
Go.
Now.
(Glinda crying softly)
You deserve each other.
(crying)
ELPHABA:
You frightened me.
For a while there,
I thought you changed.
I have changed.
This dulls the pain,
if you want a swig?
(crying)
(door opens)
No, no, no, no!
No! No! (sighs)
We've got the water, Madame.
Fools! You're too late.
Get out!
How could you let this happen?
THE WIZARD:
Uh, do you have a hairpin?
Thanks.
Uh, she and I had a deal.
But, uh...
she double-crossed me.
MADAME MORRIBLE:
We must smoke her out,
force her to show herself.
THE WIZARD:
Uh, without the monkeys,
I don't know
how we're gonna do that.
Her sister.
Use her sister.
Spread a rumor
that her sister's in trouble.
She'll fly to her side,
and you'll have her.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I need to lie down.
I have a bit of a headache.
A rumor won't do.
Elphaba's too smart.
That's right.
These things must be
done delicately.
Perhaps...
a change in the weather.
- (wind blowing)
- (objects tinkling)
♪ ♪
(crying softly)
♪ Don't wish ♪
♪ Don't start ♪
♪ Wishing only wounds
the heart ♪
♪ There's a girl I know ♪
(softly):
He loves her so.
♪ I'm not that ♪
♪ Girl. ♪
(crying)
(fabric whooshes)
(crickets chirping)
♪ ♪
♪ Kiss me too fiercely ♪
♪ Hold me too tight ♪
♪ I need help believing ♪
♪ You're with me tonight ♪
♪ My wildest dreamings ♪
♪ Could not foresee ♪
♪ Lying beside you ♪
♪ With you wanting me ♪
♪ Just for this moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ I've lost all resistance ♪
♪ And crossed some borderline ♪
♪ And if it turns out ♪
♪ It's over too fast ♪
♪ I'll make
every last moment last ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
You're beautiful.
(chuckles softly)
You don't have to lie to me.
(sighs)
It's not lying.
It's...
What is it?
It's looking at things
another way.
♪ Maybe I'm brainless ♪
♪ Maybe I'm wise ♪
♪ But you've got me seeing ♪
♪ Through different eyes ♪
♪ Somehow I've fallen ♪
♪ Under your spell ♪
♪ And somehow I'm feeling ♪
♪ It's up that I fell ♪
♪ Every moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ I'll wake up my body ♪
♪ And make up for lost time ♪
♪ Say there's no future ♪
♪ For us as a pair ♪
♪ And though I may know ♪
♪ I don't care ♪
♪ Just for this moment ♪
♪ As long as you're mine ♪
♪ Come be how you want to ♪
♪ And see how bright we shine ♪
♪ Borrow the moonlight ♪
♪ Until it is through ♪
♪ And know I'll be here ♪
♪ Holding you ♪
♪ As long as you're mine. ♪
(both chuckle)
- What is it?
- It's just...
For the first time,
I feel Wicked.
(wind whistling softly)
(rumbling)
♪ ♪
(thunder rumbling)
(thunder pulsing
to hand movements)
(wind whooshing
(thunder cracks)
(wind howling)
GUARD:
Take cover!
GUARD 2:
Get inside! Get inside!
(panicked chatter and screaming)
(wind continues howling)
(cyclone roaring)
(panicked chatter and screaming)
Boq! Boq!
Where are you?
Come on! Come on! Inside!
- (yelps)
- Stay calm.
Move! (grunts) Go!
Boq!
♪ ♪
(thunder crashing)
(wind whistling)
FIYERO:
You can't go on living here.
- They'll find you.
- I'll be all right.
Listen.
My family has a castle
in Kiamo Ko.
- Never lived in it.
- Where do you live?
In the other castle.
(chuckles):
Okay.
- Of course. -I mean,
it's the perfect hideout.
There's tunnels,
secret passageways.
You'll be safer there.
NESSAROSE (faintly):
Boq!
- Where are you?
- What?
Boq!
What is it?
What's wrong?
- (cyclone roaring)
- (thunder crashing)
This isn't gonna make
any sense, but...
There's a house.
And it's flying through the sky.
(Nessarose screaming)
(breathing heavily)
(screaming continues faintly)
(inhales sharply)
- (screaming)
- (house thuds)
- (breathing heavily)
- Hey, hey, hey.
My sister.
- She's in danger.
I have to get to her. -What?
- I'm coming with you.
- No.
It's too dangerous.
Will we ever see
each other again?
(breathes deeply)
Elphaba, we are going to be
together always.
You can see houses
flying through the sky,
- but you can't see that?
- (chuckles)
♪ ♪
(Fiyero sighs)
- (wind roaring)
- (thunder crashing)
- (leaves rustling)
- (branches crackling)
(wind howling)
(Fiyero grunting)
(panting)
(monkeys screeching)
(thunder crashing)
(birds chirping)
(wind whistling softly)
(faint chatter in distance)
(Toto barking)
- MUNCHKIN: This way, dear.
- GLINDA: Goodbye, Dorothy.
Bye, Dodo.
It's just that one road
the whole time.
(happy chatter)
Take your time.
Hurry up, darling.
♪ ♪
(gasps softly)
(softly):
Goodbye, Nessa.
- ELPHABA: What a touching
display of grief. -Oh, shiz.
I scare you?
I seem to have
that effect on people.
I would appreciate a moment
to say goodbye to my sister.
Alone.
Of course.
Oh, Nessa.
Forgive me.
Oh, Elphaba,
don't blame yourself, please.
It's dreadful, it is.
I mean...
to have a house fall on you...
But accidents will happen.
And...
You call that an accident?
You think cyclones just appear
out of the blue?
I don't know.
I never really thought
about it...
And how dare you send
that mulish farm girl
off to see the Wizard,
as if he could do
anything to help?
She's lost. She's far from home.
She took a dead woman's shoes.
I had to do something.
I'm a public figure now.
People expect me to...
Lie?
Be encouraging.
Those shoes are all
I have left of my sister.
They weren't yours to give.
Yes, well, it seems
a lot of us are taking things
that don't belong to us now,
aren't we?
No, you just wait a clock-tick.
It might be hard for you
to comprehend
that someone like him
could choose someone like me,
but it's happened,
and it's real.
And you can wave that
ridiculous wand all you want.
You can't change it.
He never belonged to you.
He doesn't love you.
He never did.
He loves me.
Oh, my...
Feel better?
I do.
Good.
(yelps)
(scoffs)
Me, too.
(grunts) Are you crazy?
(grunts)
Excuse me.
What do you think you're doing?
(yelps) Come on!
Come on! Bring it!
ELPHABA:
Get back!
- (pants)
- (grunts)
(grunts angrily)
Get-- Oh! Oh!
(grunts fiercely) Let's go!
- (Elphaba cackling)
- (Glinda grunts)
You...
(mimics cackling)
Please.
Where'd you get that?
(wand whooshing)
What are you doing?
(strains)
(grunts)
Come on. Let's go, greenie!
Use your hands!
(both shouting)
- Come on!
- (grunting)
- Bring it on!
- You're out of your mind!
- Get off of me!
- No! -(horse neighs)
- GUARD: Attention!
- (both grunting)
- Halt in the name of the Wizard!
- GLINDA: Oh, come on!
- ELPHABA: Off of me!
- GLINDA: Ow! Ow! -Let her go.
GLINDA: No, no, no, no.
I almost had her.
- I almost had her.
- (guard grunts)
I almost had her.
- Easy.
- (grunts)
Sorry it took us so long
to get here, Your Goodness.
(gasps)
You were a part of this?
- Elphaba, no...
- I can't believe
you would stoop so low
as to use my sister's death
to capture me.
I never meant to take it
this far. I...
- Let the green girl go.
- (monkeys screeching)
Else explain to all Oz
how the Wizard's guards
watched while
Glinda the Good was slain.
(gasps)
♪ ♪
(monkey squawks)
(monkeys chattering)
- Elphaba, go.
- No. Not without you.
Go!
Go.
I...
Now.
Go.
- Please, protect her.
- (chatters)
(monkeys screeching)
(panting)
♪ ♪
(guards grunting)
(pained grunting)
No! You're hurting him!
Stop it now!
Stop it.
In the name of Goodness, stop!
(Fiyero panting)
Can't you see
he wasn't going to harm me?
He just...
He loves her.
Glinda, I am so sorry.
- (whimpers)
- Take him out to that field.
What? No, please.
Put him up on those poles
till he tells us
- where the Witch went.
- You're hurting him. No.
Fiyero! No! Please!
Let go of me!
Fiyero! Fiyero!
- (whooshing)
- (monkeys screeching)
♪ ♪
(whooshing)
(chiming and crackling)
♪ "Eleka nahmen nahmen ♪
♪ "Ah tum ah tum eleka nahmen ♪
♪ Ah tum ah tum eleka nahmen" ♪
♪ Let his flesh not be torn ♪
- ♪ Let his blood
leave no stain ♪ -(grunts)
♪ Though they beat him,
let him feel no pain ♪
♪ Let his bones never break ♪
♪ And however they try
to destroy him ♪
- ♪ Let him never die ♪
- (grunting)
♪ Let him never die ♪
♪ "Eleka nahmen nahmen ♪
♪ "Ah tum ah tum eleka nahmen ♪
♪ "Ah tum ah tum eleka ♪
- ♪ Eleka" ♪
- (grunts)
What good is this chanting?
I don't even know
what I'm reading.
♪ I don't even know
what trick I ought to try ♪
- (pained shout)
- Fiyero, where are you?
♪ Already dead or bleeding? ♪
♪ One more disaster I can add ♪
- ♪ To my generous ♪
- (rumbling)
♪ Supply? ♪
(monkeys screeching)
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ No act of charity
goes unresented ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ That's my new creed ♪
♪ My road
of good intentions led ♪
♪ Where such roads always lead ♪
♪ No good deed ♪
♪ Goes unpunished ♪
Nessa?
Dr. Dillamond.
♪ Fiyero ♪
♪ One question haunts
and hurts too much ♪
♪ Too much to mention ♪
♪ Was I really seeking good ♪
♪ Or just seeking attention? ♪
♪ Is that all good deeds are ♪
♪ When looked at
with an ice-cold eye? ♪
♪ If that's all good deeds are ♪
♪ Maybe that's the reason why ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ All helpful urges
should be circumvented ♪
♪ No good deed goes unpunished ♪
♪ Sure, I meant well ♪
♪ Well, look at
what well-meant did ♪
All right, enough! So be it!
So be it, then.
(monkeys screeching)
Let all Oz be agreed.
I'm Wicked.
♪ Through and through ♪
♪ And since I can't succeed,
Fiyero, saving you ♪
♪ I promise no good deed ♪
- ♪ Will I attempt to do again ♪
- (thunder crashing)
♪ Ever again ♪
♪ No good deed will I do ♪
♪ Again. ♪
(jaunty piano music playing)
(door opens)
You have visitors.
A girl from the land of Kansas
and three friends
she picked up along the way.
A man made of tin,
another made of straw
and a very nervous lion.
They all want something
they don't have, of course.
I'm not seeing anybody.
But these are visitors
we can use.
(door creaking)
(whimpers)
(The Lion gasps, whimpers)
(gears rattling)
Bring me the broomstick
(deep, grating voice): of the
Wicked Witch of the West...
(The Lion whimpers)
...so I have proof
that she's dead.
♪ ♪
(breathes deeply)
- OZIANS: ♪ Go and hunt her ♪
- (angry clamoring)
♪ And find her and kill her ♪
(angry clamoring continues)
♪ Go and hunt her ♪
♪ And find her and kill her ♪
(chanting):
Kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
♪ Go and hunt her ♪
♪ And find her and kill her ♪
(chanting):
Melt her! Melt her!
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
Kill her!
♪ Evil effectively eliminated ♪
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
♪ Kill the Witch ♪
Kill her! Melt her!
♪ Melt the Witch ♪
And this is more than
just a service to the Wizard.
I have a personal score
to settle with Elph--
with the Witch!
- (cheering)
- OZIAN: Yeah! Someone, kill her!
♪ It's due to her
I'm made of tin ♪
♪ Her spell made this occur ♪
♪ So for once I'm glad
I'm heartless ♪
♪ I'll be heartless
killing her! ♪
(cheering)
And I'm not the only one.
(gasping)
Tell them.
Tell them what she did to you.
How you were just a cub
and she cub-napped you.
(Ozians gasping)
♪ You see, the Lion also ♪
- ♪ Has a grievance to repay ♪
- (whimpering)
♪ If she'd let him fight
his own battles ♪
♪ When he was young ♪
♪ He wouldn't be a coward ♪
- ♪ Today ♪
- (clamoring)
- ♪ Go and hunt her ♪
- (chanting): Go! Go!
- ♪ And find her and kill her ♪
- Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Kill her! Kill her!
- Kill her!
(breathing shakily)
(sighs)
(softly):
Look.
♪ There's that beautiful girl ♪
♪ With a beautiful life ♪
♪ Such a beautiful life ♪
♪ Built on lies ♪
♪ 'Cause all that's required ♪
♪ To live in a dream ♪
♪ Is endlessly
closing your eyes ♪
♪ She spins
such beautiful stories ♪
♪ To sing her to sleep ♪
♪ Full of magic
and glory and love ♪
♪ She's the girl in the bubble ♪
♪ The bright, shiny bubble ♪
♪ Blissfully floating above ♪
♪ Ah, but the truth has a way ♪
♪ Of seeping on in ♪
♪ Beneath the surface
and sheen ♪
♪ And blind as you try to be ♪
♪ Eventually ♪
♪ It's hard to unsee
what you've seen ♪
♪ And so that beautiful girl ♪
♪ With a beautiful life ♪
♪ Has a question
that haunts her somehow ♪
♪ If she comes down
from the sky ♪
♪ Gives the real world a try ♪
♪ Who in the world is she now? ♪
♪ And though
so much of her wishes ♪
♪ That she could float on ♪
♪ And the beautiful lies
never stop ♪
♪ For the girl in the bubble ♪
♪ The pink, shiny bubble ♪
♪ It's time
for her bubble to pop ♪
♪ For the popular girl ♪
♪ High in the bubble ♪
♪ Isn't it high time ♪
♪ For her bubble ♪
♪ To pop? ♪
Madame, we have
got to stop this.
It's gone too far.
I think Elphaba can
take care of herself.
Madame.
Something has been troubling me.
(sighs)
About Nessa and that cyclone.
Sad.
I suppose it was just her time.
Was it?
Was it? What did you do?
Now, you listen to me, missy.
- (gasps) -You may be fooling
the rest of Oz,
but you're not fooling me.
- You wanted this
from the beginning. -(gasps)
"Galinda."
And now you're getting
what you wanted.
- So just do what you do best.
- No. No.
Smile.
- Wave.
- (gasps, grunts)
And shut up.
(breathing shakily)
(gasps)
♪ ♪
- I need your help.
- (horse sputtering)
♪ ♪
(neighs)
♪ Wickedness must be punished ♪
♪ Brave Witch Hunters,
I would join you if I could ♪
♪ Because Wickedness
must be punished ♪
♪ Punished, punished ♪
♪ For good ♪
- Monkeys!
- (monkeys chattering)
Find that Dorothy,
and bring back
my sister's shoes!
(monkeys screeching)
♪ ♪
(neighs)
(monkeys screeching)
(Dorothy screaming)
(neighs)
- ELPHABA: Oh, for Oz's sake,
stop crying! -(Dorothy crying)
I can't listen to it anymore.
You want to get home and see
your Aunt what's-her-name again?
- DOROTHY: Please stop.
- Then get those shoes
- off your feet!
- I'm so sorry.
- (grunts)
- (Dorothy continues crying)
- DOROTHY: I want to go home.
- (monkeys chattering)
GLINDA:
They're coming for you.
Let the little girl go.
Go away.
Elphaba, you can't
go on like this.
I can do whatever I want.
Haven't you heard?
I'm the Wicked Witch
of the West.
Chistery, at last.
What took you so long?
What is this?
Elphie, what is that?
It's Fiyero, isn't it?
Is he...
We've seen his face
for the last time.
Oh, no. (gasps)
(crying)
(Glinda continues crying)
You're right.
It's time.
I surrender.
What? Wait.
(Glinda crying)
Elphaba, what are you doing?
Glinda, you can't be found
here with me.
- You must go.
- Elphie, no. I...
Please, you must now.
Fine.
I'll go and I'll tell everyone
the truth about you,
- that you're not who they say
you are. -No, you can't.
- (exasperated sigh)
- They'll just turn against you.
- Well, I don't care.
- Well, I do.
I need you to promise that
you won't try to clear my name.
No. What? Why would I do that?
I'll tell them everything.
- Please. -No, I don't want you
to do that. Please.
I'll tell them you're not
who they say you are.
I just want you
to just listen for a minute.
- Please, please just...
- Just promise me!
Why would you ask me
to promise that?
Because they need someone
to be Wicked
so that you can be Good.
(sobs)
(voice breaking):
♪ I'm limited ♪
Just look at me.
Not with your eyes.
With theirs.
♪ I'm limited ♪
♪ And just look at you ♪
(sobs softly)
♪ You can do all I couldn't do ♪
♪ Glinda ♪
♪ ♪
Here. Take it.
- What? Elphie...
- Go on.
Take it.
But you know I...
I can't read this. I...
Well, you'll have to learn.
We can't let "Good" be
just a word.
It has to mean something.
It has to change things.
♪ Because now it's up to you ♪
(whispers):
For both of us.
♪ Now it's up to you ♪
- (sobs softly)
- You know, um...
You're the only friend
I ever had.
(chuckles softly)
And I've had so many friends.
(both laugh)
But only one that mattered.
♪ I've heard it said ♪
♪ That people come into
our lives for a reason ♪
♪ Bringing something
we must learn ♪
♪ And we are led ♪
♪ To those who help us most
to grow ♪
♪ If we let them ♪
♪ And we help them in return ♪
♪ Well, I don't know
if I believe that's true ♪
♪ But I know
I'm who I am today ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ Like a comet
pulled from orbit ♪
♪ As it passes a sun ♪
♪ Like a stream
that meets a boulder ♪
♪ Halfway through the wood ♪
♪ Who can say if I've been
changed for the better? ♪
♪ But because I knew you ♪
(chuckles, sniffles)
♪ I have been changed ♪
♪ For good ♪
♪ It well may be ♪
♪ That we will never
meet again ♪
♪ In this lifetime ♪
♪ So let me say before we part ♪
♪ So much of me is made ♪
♪ Of what I learned from you ♪
♪ You'll be with me ♪
♪ Like a handprint on my heart ♪
♪ And now whatever way
our stories end ♪
♪ I know you have
rewritten mine ♪
♪ By being my friend ♪
♪ Like a ship blown
from its mooring ♪
♪ By a wind off the sea ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped
by a sky bird ♪
♪ In a distant wood ♪
♪ Who can say if I've been
changed for the better? ♪
♪ But because I knew you ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed for good ♪
ELPHABA:
♪ And just to clear the air ♪
♪ I ask forgiveness ♪
♪ For the things I've done
you blame me for ♪
♪ But then I guess ♪
♪ We know
there's blame to share ♪
♪ And none of it seems
to matter anymore ♪
♪ Like a comet pulled
from orbit ♪
♪ Like a ship blown
from its mooring ♪
♪ As it passes a sun ♪
♪ By a wind off the sea ♪
♪ Like a stream
that meets a boulder ♪
♪ Like a seed dropped
by a bird ♪
- ♪ Halfway through the wood ♪
- ♪ In the wood ♪
♪ Who can say ♪
♪ If I've been changed
for the better? ♪
♪ I do believe I have been ♪
♪ Changed for the better ♪
(Glinda chuckles softly)
♪ And because I knew you ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed ♪
(chuckles, sniffles)
♪ For good. ♪
(crying)
(sighs)
Come on. Come on, quick.
No one can know you were here.
- (hushed): You stay here.
- What?
Everything's gonna be fine.
I love you.
I love you, too.
(both crying)
♪ ♪
(both sniffle)
(footsteps departing)
(distant rumbling)
- (distant clamoring)
- (footsteps running)
(monkey screeches)
- (distant clattering)
- (monkeys screeching)
(distant shouting)
♪ ♪
(door opens)
- (Toto barking)
- (monkeys screeching)
- (sobbing softly)
- (banging, clamoring)
♪ ♪
OZIANS:
♪ And Goodness knows ♪
♪ The Wicked's lives
are lonely ♪
(sobs softly)
(breathing shakily)
♪ Goodness knows ♪
♪ The Wicked die alone. ♪
(water splashing)
(Elphaba screaming)
(screaming fades)
♪ ♪
(sobbing softly)
Oh, Elphie.
(crying)
(Chistery grunting softly)
Miss Glinda.
(gasps)
♪ ♪
(grunts softly)
(monkeys screeching)
♪ ♪
(door opens)
She's dead.
- Do you have her broomstick?
- No.
But I do have something else
that belonged to her.
It was a keepsake.
She told me herself.
It belonged to her mother.
(sighs)
This belonged to...
...her mother?
(mutters softly)
♪ ♪
(model train bell clanging)
(model train chugging)
(whistle blowing)
(giggling)
- (chuckles)
- (gasps)
(giggling)
GLINDA:
So Elphaba was yours all along.
That's why she had such powers.
She was a child of both worlds.
Oh, my Lord.
(breathes shakily)
What have I done?
You have caused great harm.
Which is why
you will be leaving Oz.
Today.
Did you hear what I said?
And what...
what will I tell people?
Make something up.
You're good at that.
(gears rattling and clanking)
♪ ♪
(gear clangs)
(tapping on glass)
Excuse me.
Hello.
What? What do you want?
Look out your window.
Come on. (chuckles)
You don't want to miss this.
(Ozians cheering)
DOROTHY: Excuse me, please.
Don't leave without us.
Please. I-I want to go home.
Ugh, I swear it never ends
with that girl.
(Ozians exclaiming,
chattering excitedly)
The Wizard is taking
a permanent leave of absence.
Not a rumor, a fact.
The kind that is true.
Glinda, dear.
Can you not find it
in your heart t-to forgive me?
As Oz is my witness,
I can see now
how truly good you are.
Actually, I'm not.
Not yet.
But just think, Madame.
We have so many cages,
and all recently vacated.
You'll have your pick.
(chuckles)
Although I can't imagine
you'll hold up very well.
I mean, my personal opinion is
you do not have what it takes.
I hope you prove me wrong.
I doubt you will.
(monkeys chattering)
What are you doing?
Let go of me! Let...
- (screaming)
- (monkeys screeching)
♪ ♪
(wand ringing)
OZIANS:
♪ Good news... ♪
(excited chatter)
♪ She's dead ♪
♪ The Witch of the West
is dead ♪
- ♪ The Wickedest Witch
there ever was ♪ -(cheering)
♪ The enemy of all of us
here in Oz ♪
♪ Is dead ♪
♪ Good news ♪
♪ Good news. ♪
(cheering continues)
Whoo! Yep.
(chuckles)
Well, this has been fun.
As you can imagine,
I have much to attend to
with the Wizard's
unexpected departure,
so if there are no further
questions, I'm gonna go.
MUNCHKIN:
Glinda.
Is it true you were her friend?
(muffled):
What?
Sorry. One sec.
(clears throat)
(clearly):
What?
Is it true you were her friend?
(Ozians gasping, murmuring)
Friend?
Yes.
(Ozians gasping, murmuring)
I-I mean, I did know her.
(murmuring continues)
That is...
our paths did cross.
At school.
♪ ♪
Wait.
I have something more to say.
(Ozians murmuring)
Fellow Ozians...
♪ ♪
All Ozians.
(birds squawking)
- Yes, come out.
- (animals chittering)
Wherever you are, come out.
(bird chirps)
(grumbles)
Friends.
(squeaking)
Because I don't see
any enemies here.
(mooing softly)
(chittering)
(chirping)
We have been through
a frightening time.
And there will be other times
and other things
that frighten us.
But if you'll let me...
...I'd like to try to help.
To change things.
I'd like to try to be
Glinda the Good.
(Ozians cheering)
(birds chirping)
♪ ♪
(vocalizing softly)
(faint cheering)
♪ ♪
(knock)
FIYERO:
It worked.
They all think you're dead.
Fiyero?
See?
Good as new.
You saved my life.
♪ ♪
- You're beautiful.
- (chuckles)
You don't have to lie to me.
(both laugh)
It's not lying.
It's... (sighs)
It's looking at things
in another way.
Time to go.
♪ ♪
ELPHABA: I wish that Glinda
could know we're alive.
But I know she can't.
No one can ever know.
♪ ♪
(wind whistling)
(thunder rumbling softly)
♪ ♪
♪ Who can say ♪
♪ If I've been changed ♪
♪ For the better, but ♪
BOTH:
♪ Because I knew you ♪
OZIANS:
♪ No one mourns the Wicked ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ I have been changed ♪
♪ No one mourns the Wicked ♪
(whooshing)
(wind whistling)
♪ Wicked ♪
♪ Wicked. ♪
(music ends)
♪ ♪
(music fades)